softlist.net 2014-06-29

# Privacy Policy | SoftList | Freeware and Shareware Downloads Center

We are committed to protecting user's privacy and data security while surfing our site. Please find below the regulations disclosing the privacy practices implemented on the web site.

 **1\. Types of information collected and use of information**

Like most standard web sites we collect the following non-personally identifiable (technical) information: internet protocol (IP) address, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. This information is used to analyze the trends, administer the site and ensure its proper functioning. We use the tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We also analyze the search engine and search keywords use, technologies used to access our site in order to comply with search engine requirements and marketing strategies.

Personally identifiable information: visitors may surf our site anonymously without submitting any private information. We at softlist.net do not collect any personal information without a user's consent. The private information which becomes available to us is done so by a user knowingly in the following cases:

a) if a user sends us an inquiry about our services and advertising possibilities

b) if a user is nominating him-/herself as a contact person by sending us a message via online contact form

c) if a user submits a software product, thus appointing him-/herself to be an author or a contact person for the software submitted

The private data stored in this case includes: name, e-mail address, telephone and fax numbers (if submitted), business contact details. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

 **2\. Release of information**

Neither of the information collected from our visitors is shared with the third parties, nor is it sold or exchanged unless it is required by law.

 **3\. How we use cookies**

A cookie is a small text file stored on the user's computer. Cookies provide us with the technical information about the user (IP address, browser type, date and time of the visit, etc.) This information is not correlated with the user's personally-identifiable information.

Some of our business partners placing ads on our site will also use cookies to track the information about a visitor. They are used to analyze the visitor's behavior, i.e. which ad the visitor followed, how the advertiser's site was reached, IP address of a visitor, etc. Our site is also supported by Google AdSense advertising service. To serve ads to our visitors based on the contents of the site Google uses DART cookies. We have no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for external advertising companies to set them. If you wish to disable Google DART cookies, you may do so [here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html) or through your individual browser options.

 **4\. Disclaimer**

Please note that softlist.net is not responsible for the contents of the information published under software description in our catalog. Therefore please send all requests, inquiries or claims concerning the software to the author of the posting, not to the staff of softlist.net.

 **5\. Links to other web sites**

Our site contains links to other sites. Once you leave the responsibility area of our site the privacy practices of softlist.net will no longer apply. Therefore, to ensure your privacy and data security we do encourage our visitors to exercise caution and get to know the privacy statement of the corresponding site before submitting any personally identifiable information.

 **6\. Contact us**

In case of any questions about this privacy policy, the practices of this site, you can [contact us](http://www.softlist.net/contact.html).
